Guide to the William Styron Papers, 1855-2007 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings by Styron Series, 1941-1997 and undated
  - Unfinished Work Subseries, 1970-1990s and undated
    - ca. 1980-1990- "Grandfather," holograph fragment, (1 folder)
    - Early1990s- Memoir about Styron's father, (1 folder)
    - Unfinished works on Nicaragua and Carlos Fuentes, (1 folder)
  - Miscellaneous Writings Subseries, 1940-1997 and undated
    Miscellaneous writings by Styron, including a diary, unpublished short stories, an outline for a motion picture, essays, and unidentified fragments and outtakes. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1940, Wanamaker diary kept by William Styron, (1 volume) (Box WS 18)
    - 1941, Dec.8, "A Chance in a Million", (1 folder)
    - 1947, "The Brothers", (1 folder)
    - 1968, Outline for motion picture about Nat Turner, (1 folder)
    - 1992, Notes for1993calendar, (1 folder)
    - 1993, "Live on Stage", (1 folder)
    - 1997, "Grateful Words About F. Scott Fitzgerald"
    - Undated, Comments on Case Closed, by Gerald Posner, (1 folder)
    - Undated, Unpublished essay on Russia, (1 folder)
    - Undated, Essay on taking long walks, (1 folder)
    - Undated, Essay about homosexuality, (1 folder)
    - Undated, Essay on Alexander Cockburn, (1 folder)
    - Undated, Fragment of "Marriott the Marine", (1 folder)
    - Undated, Miscellaneous essays, (1 folder)
    - Undated, Outtakes, (1 folder)
    - Undated, Untitled fragments, (5 folders)
- Writings by Others Series, 1958-1995and undated
  Papers and theses by other authors on Styron's work, typescripts and photocopies of works sent to Styron by other authors, screenplays of works by Styron, and limited editons of poetry sent to Styron by other authors. Includes a sermon on Nat Turner by James Cleland, a signed typescript of "La obra maestra de William Styron" by Carlos Fuentes, and autographed limited editions of Reynolds Price's "Christ Child's Song at the End of the Night," and "The Annual Heron," as well as a limited edition of Allen Tate's "All is Brillig (Or Ought to Be)." The last box contains interviews with Styron. Arranged alphabetically by name of author.
  - Aubry, Martine - "William Styron and the Aesthetics of Failure,"1976, (1 folder) (Box WO 1)
  - Brunstein, Robert - "Styron's Choice," undated, (1 folder)
  - Bunker, Ed - Collection of short stories, ca. 1982, (1 folder)
  - Clark, Whitehurst - "Turkey Feathers," undated, (1 folder)
  - Cleland, James T. - Sermon on Nat Turner,1968, (1 folder)
  - Core, George - "The Confessions of Nat Turner and the Burden of the Past," undated, (1 folder)
  - Elliott, Shannon - "Exploration of Grief,"1992, (1 folder)
  - Fuentes, Carlos - "La obra maestra de William Styron," [1981?], (1 folder)
  - Gardener, John - Notes preceding his review of Sophie's Choice, undated, (1 folder)
  - Gibb, Sharon - "Styron's Turner vs. Dr. Herbert Aptheker," undated, (1 folder)
  - Huffman, James - "A Psychological Redefinition of Styron's The Confessions of Nat Turner," undated, (1 folder)
  - Leon, Philip - Styron bibliography,1978, (1 folder)
  - Morris, Willie - Book of the Month Club News,1979, (1 folder)
  - Morris, Willie - "Dear Mom, They're at it Again...," undated, (1 folder)
  - Pakula, Alan - Screenplay of "Sophie's Choice,"1982, (1 folder) (Box WO 2)
  - Pakula, Alan - Revised screenplay of "Sophie's Choice,"1983, (2 folders)
  - Parrish, James A. - "No Home to Go Home To," undated, (1 folder)
  - Peterson, Louis - Screenplay for Set This House on Fire, undated, (1 folder)
  - Price, Reynolds - "Christ Child's Song at the End of the Night,"1978, (1 folder)
  - Price, Reynolds - "The Annual Heron,"1979, (1 folder)
  - Rockwell, Riffin - "For William Blackburn,"1973, (1 folder) (Box WO 3)
  - St. Phalle, Therese de - "William Styron: Roots of Creativity,"1986
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr - "Introduction to William Styron," 1995, Feb. 1, (1 folder)
  - Styron, Polly - Diary excerpts, undated, (1 folder)
  - Styron, Susanna and Bridget Terry - "Shadrach: A Screenplay," [1997?], (1 folder)
  - Styron, William, Sr. - "The Genesis of William Styron," undated, (1 folder)
  - Styron, William, Sr. - "Stories for his grandchildren," ca. 1958, (1 folder)
  - Tate, Allen - "All is Brillig (Or Ought to Be),"1979, (1 folder)
  - Torck Valentine - "William Styron's Sophie's Choice,"1984, (1 folder)
  - Interviews (Box WO 4)
    - Ellsberg, Daniel - Interview with Styron,1972, (1 folder)
    - Kroll, Daniel - Interview with Styron, undated, (1 folder)
    - Plimpton, George - Interview with Styron,1967, (1 folder)
    - Rahv, Philip - Interview with Styron, undated, (1 folder)
    - Shabalov, Ray - Interview with Styron,1967, (1 folder)
    - Yale interview with Styron,1967, (1 folder)
    - Unidentified interview with Styron, undated, (1 folder)
- Printed Material Series, 1900-1998 and undated
  The printed material series is divided into the following groups: Serials containing material by or pertaining to Styron (arranged chronologically); Volumes which belonged to Styron or which contain material by or about him (arranged chronologically); Clippings pertaining to Styron and his work (some folders arranged chronologically and a few by topic); and Miscellaneous Printed Material (arranged chronologically). The William Styron Oversize Box contains other material in this series.
  - Serials Group
    - 1944-1946,Duke Archive (6 issues) (Box PM 1)
      Boxed set of Styron's copies
    - 1945, May 14, Archive Time (1 copy)
      Note in Styron's hand refers to article on J. Foster Barnes on p. 22
    - 1952, Jan., Omnibook (1 copy)
      Lie Down in Darkness (Abridged, p. 69)
    - 1954, Spring, The Paris Review (1 copy)
      Interview: "The Art of Fiction V" (p. 43)
    - 1958, Spring, The Paris Review (1 copy)
      Styron was advisory editor.
    - 1959, April6, The New Republic (1 copy)
      "If You Write for Television... " (p. 16)
    - 1960, Autumn-Winter, The Paris Review (1 copy)
      "The McCabes" (p. 12)
    - 1960, May 30, Publishers' Weekly (1 copy)
      "William Styron Writes PW about His New Novel" (p.54)
    - 1960, Summer, Critique (1 copy)
      "Styron and His Students" by Robert Gorham Davis (p. 37); "Styron and the Fiction of the Fifties" by David L. Stevenson (p. 47); "An Orgy of Commerce: William Styron's Set This House on Fire" by Richard Foster (p. 59); "Two Bibliographies: Saul Bellow, William Styron" by Harold W. Schneider (p. 71)
    - 1961, Sum./Fall, The Paris Review (1 copy)
      Poems translated by Rose Styron: Ossip Mandelstam, Marina Tsvetayeva, Andrei Vozneisenski (p. 135)
    - 1961, Nov., Esquire (1 copy)
      "Mrs. Aadland's Little Girl, Beverly" (p. 142)
    - 1962, Apr.,Wilson Library Bulletin (1 copy)
      "WLB Biography: William Styron" by A. H. Cheyer (p. 691)
    - 1962, Spring, Voices (1 copy)
      Symposium: "The Role of the Writer in America" (p. 7)
    - 1962, Nov., Esquire (1 copy)
      "The Aftermath of Benjamin Reid" (p. 79)
    - 1963, July, Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "Two Writers Talk It Over" by James Jones and William Styron (p.57)
    - 1963, Autumn, The South Atlantic Quarterly (1 copy)
      "The Hopeful Stoicism of William Styron" by Jerry H. Bryant (p. 539)
    - 1963-64, Winter, Mississippi Quarterl y (1 copy)
      "The Triumph Over Time: Narrative Form in William Faulkner and William Styron" by Marvin Klotz (p. 9)
    - 1965, Apr., Harper's Magazine (1 copy)
      This Quiet Dust (p. 135)
    - 1965, June, Revista de la Universidad de México (1 copy)
      "Las memorias de MacAuthur" (translated by Carlos Monsiváis, p. 11)
    - 1965, Summer, The American Scholar (1 copy)
      Styron's copy
    - 1966, Jan., High Fidelity (1 copy)
      "John Fitzgerald Kennedy... As We Remember Him" (p. 38)
    - 1965-66, Winter, Critique (1 copy)
      "Expense of Spirit: The Vision of William Styron" by Shaun O' Connell (p. 20); "William Styron's Don Juan" by Kenneth A. Robb (p. 34); "The Broader Vision: William Styron's Set This House on Fire" by Gunnar Urang (p. 47); "The Nature of Rebellion in The Long March" by Peter L. Hays (p. 70); "Robert Penn Warren, William Styron, and the Use of Greek Myth" by L. Hugh Moore (p. 75)
    - 1966, Winter, The Paris Review (1 copy)
      "Virginia:1831" (p. 14)
    - 1966, Oct., La Nouvelle Revue Français (1 copy)
      "Poussière paisible" (part I, translated by Didier Coupaye and Claude Lévy, p. 649)
    - 1966, Nov., La Nouvelle Revue Français (1 copy)
      "Poussière paisible" (part II, translated by Didier Coupaye and Claude Lévy, p. 852)
    - 1966, Fall, Partisan Review (1 copy)
      "Runaway" (p. 575)
    - 1967, Sept., Harper's Magazin e (1 copy)
      The Confessions of Nat Turner (Excerpts, p. 52)
    - 1967, Oct.7, Saturday Review (1 copy)
      "Race Riot,1831" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turner by Granville Hicks, p. 29)
    - 1967, Oct. 13, Life (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "The Novelist as a Rebel Slave. William Styron Goes Back to1831and the Soul of Nat Turner" (p. 51); "Novel's Climax: The Night of the Honed Axes" (an excerpt from The Confessions of Nat Turner, p. 54)
    - 1967, Oct. 13,T ime (1 copy)
      "Ideas of Hope" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turner, p. 110)
    - 1967, Oct. 16, Newsweek (1 copy)
      "Into the Mind of Nat Turner" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turner by Raymond A. Sokolov, p. 65)
    - 1967, Nov. 25, The New Yorker (1 copy)
      "The Fire Last Time" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turne r by George Steiner, p. 236)
    - 1967, Nov., Yale Alumni Magazine (1 copy)
      "Slavery in the First Person" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turner and an interview with the author by R.W.B. Lewis and C. Vann Woodward, p. 33)
    - 1967, Dec., Vogue (1 copy)
      "Styron Unlocked" by John Phillips (p.216)
    - 1967, Dec., The Hollins Critic (1 copy)
      "William Styron and Human Bondage: The Confessions of Nat Turner" by Louis D. Rubin, Jr.
    - 1968, Jan., Playboy (1 copy)
      Piece by Art Buchwald in which Styron plays an important role: "Paper Plimpton" (p. 143)
    - 1968, Jan., The Seahorse (1 copy)
      "Alumnus William Styron Tops the Best Seller List" by Neil Rabin (p.1)
    - 1968, Feb., Harper's Magazine (1 copy)
      "The Vice That Has No Name" (p. 97)
    - 1968, Apr., Harper's Magazine (1 copy)
      "The Shade of Thomas Wolfe" (p. 96)
    - 1968, May3, The Daily Telegraph (1 copy)
      "The Quiet Dust" (p. 7)
    - 1968, July 13, Saturday Review (1 copy)
    - 1968, July 20, Saturday Review (1 copy)
    - 1968, July, McCall's (1 copy)
      "The Oldest America" (p. 94)
    - 1968, Oct., Esquire (1 copy)
      "My Generation" (p. 123)
    - 1968, Summer, The American Scholar (1 copy)
      Symposium: "Violence in Literature" (p. 482)
    - 1968, Summer, Partisan Review (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "The Turner Thesis" by Michael Thelwell (p. 402)
    - 1968, Summer, The Southern Review (1 copy)
      "Nat Turner and the final Reckoning of Things" by George Core (p. 745)
    - 1968, Summer, Tufts Alumni Review (1 copy)
      Notice of Styron's honorary degree of Doctor of Letters from Tufts (p. 11)
    - 1968, Fall, Yale Literary Magazine (1 copy)
      "The Case Against William Styron's Nat Turner" by Robert Sussman (p. 20); "William Styron on The Confessions of Nat Turner: A Yale Lit Interview" by Douglas Barzelay and Robert Sussman (p. 24)
    - 1968, Fourth Quarter, The Whetstone (1 copy)
      "Reflections on Nat Turner" by Rev. James T. Cleland (p. 8)
    - 1968, Contemporary Writers in Christian Perspective (1 copy)
      "William Styron. A Critical Essay" by Robert H. Fossum
    - 1969, Jan 20-26, L'Express (1 copy)
      "Les confessions de Nat Turner" (excerpts from the French translation by Mourice-Edgar Coindreau, p. 92)
    - 1969, Jan. 20-Feb. 2, L'Express (1 copy)
      "Les confessions de Nat Turner" (excerpts from the French translation by Mourice-Edgar Coindreau, p. 86)
    - 1969, Feb. 3-9, L'Express (1 copy)
    - 1969, Spring, The Southern Literary Journal (1 copy)
      "The Uses of History in Fiction" (a panel discussion with Ralph Ellison, William Styron and Robert Penn Warren, C. Vann Woodward, moderator, p. 57)
    - 1969, Summer, Contemporary Literature (1 copy)
      "Negro Literature and Classic Form" by Nancy M. Tischler (p. 352)
    - 1970, Spring, The Southern Literary Journal (1 copy)
      "The Confessions of Nat Turner and the Burden of the Past" by George Core (p. 117)
    - 1970, Autumn, The Southern Review (1 copy)
    - 1971, Sept., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "Marriott, the Marine" (p. 101)
    - 1971, Nov., Duke Alumni Register (1 copy)
      "Dubious Submission and Willing Fate" (interview with James Wise, p. 4)
    - 1971, Spring/Summer, The Barat Review (1 copy)
      Introduction by Nancy M. Tischler (p. 3); "A Letter From William Styron" (p. 5); "Styron's Nat Turner: A Search for Humanity" by Jean S. Mullen (p. 6); "Black and White: The Archetypal Myth and its Development" by Dalma H. Brunaur (p. 12); "Nat Turner's Mysticism" by Blair Whitney (p. 21); "Nat Turner: God, Man, or Beast?" by Patricia R. Cannon (p. 25); "Christ as Revolutionary / Revolutionary as Christ: The Hero in Bernard Malamud's The Fixer and William Styron's The Confessions of Nat Turner" by Sanford Pinsker (p. 29)
    - 1971, Autumn, The Southern Review (1 copy)
      "Rebellion of Wrath and Laughter: Styron's Set This House on Fire" by Marc L. Ratner (p. 1007)
    - 1972, March,I ntellectual Digest (1 copy)
      "William Styron on Our Literature of Collision" (interview by Philip Rahv, p. 82)
    - 1972, March, The Washington Monthly (1 copy)
      "The Red Badge of Literature" (a review of Ronald J. Glasser's 365 Days by Styron, p. 32)
    - 1972, March, The Atlantic Monthly (1 copy)
      Letter to the editor about remarks attributed to Styron (p. 27)
    - 1972, Aug., Esquire (1 copy)
      "Checking in with William Styron" by Daniel Halpern (p. 142)
    - 1972, Dec., Ploughshares (1 copy)
      "Reflections" (p. 82)
    - 1973, July 30, Time (1 copy)
      "Martha's Troubled Vineyard" (article about Martha's Vineyard in which Styron is mentioned, p. 42)
    - 1974, Feb., American Heritage (1 copy)
      "History Versus Historical Fiction" (Styron's response to an article published in a previous issue of AH, p. 101)
    - 1974, Aug./Sept., Southern Voices (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      Styron's Copy (article by Eugene D. Genovese on the slave family marked, p. 9)
    - 1974, Autumn, The Southern Review (1 copy)
      "An Interview with William Styron" by Ben Forkner and Gilbert Schricke (p. 923)
    - 1975, Jan., The Literary Half-yearly (1 copy)
      "The Agony of a Slave Negro: Theme and Technique in Styron's Nat Turner" by K. P. Saradhi (p. 6)
    - 1975, Spring, Mississippi Quarterly (1 copy)
      "William Styron's Afterword to The Long March" by James L. W. West III (p. 185); "Afterword" (p. 187)
    - 1975, Costerus (1 copy)
      "A Bibliographer's Interview with William Styron" by James L. W. West III (p. 13)
    - 1976, Sept., Esquire (1 copy)
      "The Seduction of Leslie" (p. 92)
    - 1976, Winter, American Studies International (1 copy)
      "Race, Ideology and Scholarship in the United States: William Styron's Nat Turner and its Critics" by Okon E. Uya (p. 63)
    - 1977, Sept., Bookviews (1 copy)
      "Happy Moments at the Mailbox. Some Celebrated Authors describe..."by Peter Gardner (p. 10)
    - 1977, Spring, The Archive (1 copy)
      "An Interview with William Styron" by Marc Stanford (p. 84); "The Force of Her Happiness" (excerpt from Sophie's Choice,, p. 94)
    - 1977, Spring, Mississippi Quarterly (1 copy)
      "Discussions with William Styron" by Ray Ownbey (p. 283)
    - 1977, Island (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "An Interview with William Styron" by Michael West (p. 47)
    - 1978, March 14, Esquire Fort Nightly (1 copy)
      "My Life as a Publisher" (p. 71)
    - 1978, Nov. 21, Esquire Fort Nightly (1 copy)
      "Shadrach" (p. 82)
    - 1978, Summer, Bulletin of the Center for the Study of Southern Culture and Religion (1 copy)
      "William Styron on Nat Turner" (p. 1)
    - 1978, Fall, Cross Currents (1 copy)
      Issue concerning the Holocaust. Passages marked by Styron.
    - 1978-1979, Esquire Fort Nightly (1 copy)
      "Shadrach" (p. 46)
    - 1978-79, Winter, Taproot (1 copy)
      "Introduction" (p. D)
    - 1979, March, Nagyvilág (1 copy)
      "Lektorkorom emlékezete" (Elbeszélés, Ungvári Tamás fordítása, p. 326)
    - 1979, June, Horizon (1 copy)
      "William Styron. An 'Unfamous' Great Writer Brings Out a New Novel, Sophie's Choice" by Andrew Fielding (p. 60)
    - 1979, July 23, People (1 copy)
      "From Slavery to Holocaust, Author Bill Styron Makes Best-Selling Choices" by Andrea Chambers (p.67)
    - 1979, July, Vogue (1 copy)
      "The Novel of the Year: William Styron's New Novel, Sophie's Choice (p. 164); "Styron's Choice" by Robert Brustein (p. 166)
    - 1979, Aug. 27, Newsweek (1 copy)
      "Newsweek Newsmakers" (Styron mentioned among authors protesting the new American Book Awards, p. 42)
    - 1979, Aug., Look (1 copy)
      "A Conversation with William Styron" by Peter H. Stone (p. 33)
    - 1979, First Quarter, The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America (1 copy)
      "The Second Serials of This Side of Paradise and The Beautiful and the Damned" by James L. W. West III (p. 63)
    - 1979, Summer, The Student (1 copy)
      "William Styron's Sophie's Choice: Evoking the Evil of Auschwitz Through a Polish-Catholic Heroine" by Alyce Woody and Wade Hampton (p. 40)
    - 1979, Winter, Contemporary Literature (1 copy)
      "An Interview with William Styron" conducted by Valerie Meliotes Arms (p. 1)
    - 1979 Winter, The Hampden-Sydney Poetry Review (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "The Writer's Power: An Interview with William Styron, James Dickey and Willie Morris" by Tom O'Grady (p. --)
    - 1980, May, South Atlantic Bulletin (1 copy)
      "Almost a Rhodes Scholar: A Personal Reminiscence" (p. 1)
    - 1980, July-Aug., Realities (1 copy)
      "In Praise of Vineyard Haven" (p. 54)
    - 1980, Sept., Saturday Review (1 copy)
      "Creators on Creating: William Styron" by Hilary Mills (p. 46)
    - 1980, Nov., Horizon (1 copy)
      "American Writers in Paris" by Ben Yagoda (p. 26)
    - 1980-81, Winter, Mississippi Quarterly (1 copy)
      "William Styron: A Biographical Account" by James L. W. West III (p. 3); "Bearing the Unbearable: William Styron and the Problem of Pain" by John L. Cobbs (p. 15); "William Styron and the Spell of the South" by Valerie Meliotes Arms (p. 25); "Styron's False Start: The Discarded Opening for Set This House on Fire" by Arthur D. Casciato (p. 36)
    - 1980, Fall, Christchurch (1 copy)
      "Styron's Choice" by Pam White
    - 1981, Jan., American Literature (1 copy)
      "William Styron and The Southhampton Insurrection" by Arthur D. Casciato and James L. W. West III (p. 564)
    - 1981, Aug. 10, Elle (1 copy)
      "Hanté par le souvenir d'une femme" by Katherine Pancol (p. 76)
    - 1981, Nov. 30-Dec. 6, Le Point (1 copy)
      "Jean-François Fogel fail le point avec William Styron" by Jean-François Fogel (p.143)
    - 1982, Jan., Esquire (1 copy)
      "The Conversation. Candice Bergen and William Styron" (p. 86)
    - 1982, Fall, The Stingaree (1 copy)
      "Christchurch to Host Sophie's Choice Premier" (p. 1)
    - 1982, Modern Literature First Editions (1 copy)
      Catalogue, Photo of Styron on the cover
    - 1983, Jan., Moviegoer (1 copy)
      "Meryl Streep and Kevin Kline" by William Wolf (p. 9)
    - 1983, Apr., Commonwealth (1 copy)
      "Styron's Choice" by Lisa M. Antonelli (p. 39)
    - 1983, Dec., Esquire (1 copy)
      "The Short Classy Voyage of JFK" (p. 124)
    - 1984, Jan 6, Publishers Weekly (1 copy) (Box PM 9)
      Quote from Styron about novel in progress (p. 60)
    - 1984, Sept.-Oct., Duke (1 copy)
      "Inside the Creative Mind" by Georgann Eubanks (p. 2)
    - 1984, Dec., Vanity Fair (1 copy)
      "In Celebration of Capote" (p. 120)
    - 1984, Summer, The Southern Review (1 copy)
      "I, Stingo: The Problem of Egotism in Sophie's Choice" by William Heath (p. 528)
    - 1986, Summer, Southern Coalition Report on Jail and Prisons (1 copy)
    - 1986, Fall, Tidings (1 copy)
      "Styron Reminisces about Boyhood on the James" (p. 6)
    - 1987, Mar.7, The Nation (1 copy)
      A Symposium: "Cigarette Ads and the Press" (p. 283)
    - 1987, Aug., Esquire (1 copy)
      "A Tidewater Morning" (p. 85)
    - 1987, Winter, Southern Coalition Report on Jails and Prison (1 copy)
    - 1988, Nov. 11, L'Express (1 copy)
      "Styron: vive Jefferson" with Jacques Renard (p.8)
    - 1988, Fall/Winter, Colony News (1 copy)
      Issue devoted to Styron's being awarded the MacDowell Medal
    - 1989, Dec., Vanity Fair (1 copy)
      "Darkness Visible" (p. 212)
    - 1989-1990,Fall/Winter, Martha's Vineyard (1 copy)
      "William Styron Speaks His Mind" with William Marks (p. 36)
    - 1989, Focus (1 copy)
      "William Styron Visits NCSU" by Jinnie Davis (p. 1)
    - 1990, Jan., North Carolina State (1 copy)
      "The Legacy Renewed" by Terri Leith (p. 7); "The Works of William Styron" by Terri Leith (p. 9)
    - 1990, Dec.-1991, Jan., Duke (1 copy)
      Review of Darkness Visible: a Memoir of Madness by H. Keith H. Brodie, M.D. (p. 50); Excerpt from Darkness Visible (p. 51)
    - 1991, Mar. 21,Image (1 copy)
      "Through a Glass Darkly" by Mark Hertsgaard (p. 10)
    - 1993, Winter/Spring, Duke University Libraries (1 copy)
      Address to the City Lights Society (p. 2)
    - 1995, Sept. 18, The New Yorker (1 copy)
      "A Case of the Great Pox" (p. 62)
    - 1995, Oct.8, The New York Times Magazine (1 copy)
      "A Horrid Little Racist" (p. 80)
    - 1995, Spring, Traces (1 copy)
      "I'll Have to Ask Indianapolis" (p. 4)
    - Excerpt from Lie Down in Darkness (p. 13)
      "Ordeal and Renewal. David Laurence Chambers, Hiram Haydn, and Lie Down in Darkness" by J. Kent Calder (p. 14)
    - Undated, Esquire (1 copy)
      "William Styron" by Walt Sandulli and Paul Duke (p. 25)
  - Volumes Group
    - 1900 - The Southampton Insurrection, by William Sidney Drewry (Box PM 10)
      Styron's copy with his marginalia.
    - 1924 - Eneas Africanus, by Harry Stillwell Edwards
    - 1961 - John Hartwell Cocke of Bremo. Agriculture and Slavery in the Ante-bellum South, by M. Boyd Coyner, Jr.
    - 1965 - An Examination of the Psychological Validity of Characters in 'Lie Down in Darkness', by Helen Slaby Mills
    - 1972 - To Choose Being: The Function of Order and Disorder in William Styron's Fiction, by Ray Wilson Ownbey (Box PM 11)
    - 1973 - Esquire. The Best of Forty Years
      "My Generation," p. 13.
    - 1974 - Idea and Technique in the Novels of William Styron, by Philip W. Leon
    - 1974 - The Novels of William Styron. An Existential Study, by S. Laxmana Murphy
    - 1976 - The Development of William Styron's Artistic Consciousness: A Study of the Relationship Between Life and Work, by Eva Bamberger Mills (Box PM 12)
    - 1977 - William Styron's Literary Career, by Valerie Meliotes Arms
    - 1979 - The Best American Short Stories 1979, ("Shadrach," p. 56) (Box PM 13)
    - 1985 - Conversations with William Styron, edited by James L. W. West III
      Proof.
    - 1987 - The Nightmare of History in William Styron's 'The Confessions of Nat Turner,' by Daniel Fabricant
  - Clippings Group
    - Pre-1950-1989, (18 folders) (Box PM 14)
    - 1990-98, undated, (7 folders) (Box PM 15)
    - Clippings in French
    - French articles, Cette paisible poussière
    - Foreign Languages other than French
    - Articles on Darkness Visible
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, (3 folders)
    - The Confessions of Nat Turner, (9 folders) (Box PM 16)